<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE Book SYSTEM "gapdoc.dtd">

<Book Name="SgpDec">

<TitlePage>
<Title>The <Package>SgpDec</Package> Package</Title>
<Version>Version 0.7</Version>
<Author>Attila Egri-Nagy <Email>A.Egri-Nagy@herts.ac.uk</Email></Author>
<Author>Chrystopher L. Nehaniv<Email>C.L.Nehaniv@herts.ac.uk</Email></Author>
<Author>James Mitchell<Email>jdm3@st-and.ac.uk</Email></Author>

<TitleComment>
Hierarchical composition and decomposition of finite permutation groups and
transformation semigroups.
</TitleComment>

<Abstract>
This  <Package>GAP4.5</Package> package contains a computational implementation
of hierarchical decompositions of transformation semigroups
(Krohn-Rhodes theory) and permutation groups. Cascaded structures (substructures
of the wreath product) can be constructed by explicitly giving the dependency
 functions between the components or can be obtained by the decomposition
 algorithms (holonomy for semigroups, Lagrange decompositon for groups).
</Abstract>

<Copyright>&copyright; Attila Egri-Nagy, Chrystopher L. Nehaniv, James Mitchell.
</Copyright>

</TitlePage>

<TableOfContents/>


<Body>
<!--##### Chapters/sections are in individual xml files. -->


<Chapter> <Heading>Words</Heading>
<Section>
<Heading>Words as list of integers</Heading>
In <Package>SgpDec</Package> words are represented as dense lists of positive
integers.
The integers usually code the indices of elements of some generator set, thus
they should be between 1 and the size of the generator set. 
<#Include Label="Construct">
</Section>

<Section>
<Heading>Straight words</Heading>
If a word constructs a trajectory without repeated elements then we say that
it is straight (the start point can be repeated at the end)
<Cite Key="straightwords2010"/> .
Note that the word itself can contain repeated symbols.
<#Include Label="IsStraightWord">
<#Include Label="Reduce2StraightWord">
</Section>

<Section>
<Heading>Enumerating straight words</Heading>
A backtrack algorithm is used to go through the straight words.
Whenever the search finds a straight word a processor function is called.
Using these plugins  the backtrack algorithm can do many different things
with the results.

<#Include Label="StraightWords">
<#Include Label="SWP_Printer">
<#Include Label="SWP_SimpleCollector">
<#Include Label="SWP_WordPointPairCollector">
<#Include Label="SWP_Search">

</Section>


</Chapter>
</Body>

<Bibliography Databases="SGPDEC" />
</Book>
