<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE Book SYSTEM "gapdoc.dtd">

<Book Name="SgpDec">

<TitlePage>
<Title>The <Package>SgpDec</Package> Package</Title>
<Version>Version 0.7</Version>
<Author>Attila Egri-Nagy <Email>A.Egri-Nagy@herts.ac.uk</Email></Author>
<Author>Chrystopher L. Nehaniv<Email>C.L.Nehaniv@herts.ac.uk</Email></Author>
<Author>James Mitchell<Email>jdm3@st-and.ac.uk</Email></Author>

<TitleComment>
Hierarchical composition and decomposition of finite permutation groups and
transformation semigroups.
</TitleComment>

<Abstract>
This  <Package>GAP4.5</Package> package contains a computational implementation
of hierarchical decompositions of transformation semigroups
(Krohn-Rhodes theory) and permutation groups. Cascaded structures (substructures
of the wreath product) can be constructed by explicitly giving the dependency
 functions between the components or can be obtained by the decomposition
 algorithms (holonomy for semigroups, Lagrange decompositon for groups).
</Abstract>

<Copyright>&copyright; Attila Egri-Nagy, Chrystopher L. Nehaniv, James Mitchell.
</Copyright>

</TitlePage>

<TableOfContents/>


<Body>
<!--##### Chapters/sections are in individual xml files. -->

<Chapter> <Heading>Introduction</Heading>

 <#Include SYSTEM "install.xml">
 <#Include SYSTEM "conf.xml">

</Chapter>

<Chapter>
<Heading>Holonomy Decomposition</Heading>
The holonomy decomposition is constructed based on the action of the semigroup
on the orbit of the state set.
<Section Label="Skeleton">
<Heading>Skeleton</Heading>
<#Include Label="Skeleton">
<#Include Label="ImageSets">
<#Include Label="CoveringSetsOf">
<#Include Label="DepthOfSet">
<#Include Label="TopSet">
<#Include Label="SkeletonClasses">
<#Include Label="RepresentativeSet">


The subsemigroup stabilizing a subset X of the state set is called the
permutator subsemigroup (to avoid name clash). Restricting this permutator to
$X$ gives the permutator group (Generalized Schützenberger group, see  
<Cite Key="permutator"/> )
<#Include Label="PermutatorSemigroup">
<#Include Label="PermutatorGenerators">
<#Include Label="AllPermutators">
<#Include Label="PermutatorGroup">
<#Include Label="CoverGroup">
</Section>

</Chapter>

<Chapter> <Heading>Finite Sets</Heading>
For representing finite sets of positive integers we can use lists.
However, it we store a lot of these sets then we need to use boolean lists
to save space. On the other hand dealing with boolean lists would provide
an inelegant solution for the <Package>SgpDec</Package> user.
That is why we introduce this new data type.
Many set operations are reimplemented and a few specialized functions
used in decompositions are also included.
<Section>
<Heading>Constructors</Heading>
<#Include Label="FiniteSet">
If the underlying <C>BList</C> is constructed beforehand, then
<C>FiniteSetByBlist</C> can be used to wrap the boolean list.
For copying an exisiting finite set <C>FiniteSetCopy</C> can be used.
</Section>

<Section>
<Heading>Properties of finite sets</Heading>
<#Include Label="SizeOfUniverse">
<#Include Label="IsSingleton">
</Section>

<Section>
<Heading>Set operations</Heading>
Most operations for sets are implemented for finite sets.
The function names have the <C>FiniteSet</C> suffix.
The other useful convention used is that if the name of the operation is a noun
then it returns a new instance of a finite set e.g. <C>UnionFiniteSet</C>,
if it is a verb then it changes the (first) parameter,
e.g. <C>UniteFiniteSet</C>.
</Section>

<Section>
<Heading>Acting on finite sets</Heading>
<#Include Label="OnFiniteSets">
<#Include Label="IsIdentityOnFiniteSet">
</Section>

</Chapter>


<Chapter> <Heading>Words</Heading>
<Section>
<Heading>Words as list of integers</Heading>
In <Package>SgpDec</Package> words are represented as dense lists of positive
integers.
The integers usually code the indices of elements of some generator set, thus
they should be between 1 and the size of the generator set.
<#Include Label="Construct">
</Section>

<Section>
<Heading>Straight words</Heading>
If a word constructs a trajectory without repeated elements then we say that
it is straight (the start point can be repeated at the end)
<Cite Key="straightwords2010"/> .
Note that the word itself can contain repeated symbols.
<#Include Label="IsStraightWord">
<#Include Label="Reduce2StraightWord">
</Section>

<Section>
<Heading>Enumerating straight words</Heading>
A backtrack algorithm is used to go through the straight words.
Whenever the search finds a straight word a processor function is called.
Using these plugins  the backtrack algorithm can do many different things
with the results.

<#Include Label="StraightWords">
<#Include Label="SWP_Printer">
<#Include Label="SWP_SimpleCollector">
<#Include Label="SWP_WordPointPairCollector">
<#Include Label="SWP_Search">
</Section>
</Chapter>

<Chapter> <Heading>Misc</Heading>
<Section>

<Heading>Linear notation for transformations</Heading>
Following the notation described in <Cite Key="ClassicalTransSemigroups2009"/> we use a one-line compact notation for finite transformations. 
<#Include Label="LinearNotation">
</Section>
</Chapter>

</Body>

<Bibliography Databases="SGPDEC" />
</Book>
